Minh Do

Website: http://minhdo.tech/ | Email: minhdo.ca@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/TheShadow8/

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/minhdoca/

Summary

I am a Software Engineer with 6 years of experience in Web Development. I have 3 years of experience in Modern Front-end and 6 year of Backend / Devops .

With a bachelor's degree in Business Administration, I have worked with a number of startups in entertainment, finance, human resources industries using a variety of technologies such as AI, Blockchain etc

Technical skills

Programming Language: Golang, Javascript & Typescript, Solidity, Rust, Java, Lua

Framework / Platforms / Blockchain:

Gin, Fiber, Echo, Go-micro

ReactJs, NextJs, NodeJs, NestJs

Hardhat, Remix

Ethereum Virtual Machine blockchains, HyperLedger Fabric,

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDb, Firebase, Redis, RabbitMQ Devops: Gitlab CI/CD, Docker, Kubernetes, PM2, AWS, Alibaba Cloud, GCP

Soft skills

Communication, Patience, Open-Mindedness, Problem Solving, Critical Thinking, Time Management, Collaboration

Languages

Vietnamese, English and Chinese

Work Experience

MetaLoka / CEO

2021 - Current: Hanoi, Vietnam

- Develop high quality business strategies and plans ensuring their alignment with short-term and longterm objectives.
- Lead and motivate subordinates to advance employee engagement develop a high performing managerial team.
- Oversee all operations and business activities to ensure they produce the desired results and are consistent with the overall strategy and mission.
- Build trust relations with key partners and stakeholders and act as a point of contact for important shareholders.
- Maintain a deep knowledge of the markets and industry of the company.

Bytesoft Vietnam / Technical Manager

2019 - Current: Hanoi, Vietnam

- Research, Design, develop and test Blockchain Technologies, Hyperledger Fabric.
- Work with teams to create blockchain application-related deployment, configuration, monitoring, and integration software components.
- Developing smart contracts and blockchain-based applications on Ethereum Virtual Machine blockchains / Hyperledger Fabric.
- Code in various fit to purpose languages for Ethereum Virtual Machine blockchains / Hyperledger Fabric end-to-end solutions such as Solidity, Go, and JavaScript.
- Brainstorm and help evaluate applications for new tools and technologies as they continually evolve.
 Implemented new UI and templating system to improve UX and system flexibility.
- Maintain and extend current client- and server-side applications responsible for integration and business logic.
- Build around use cases, depending on the application requirement.
- Integrate and use leading open source tools such as MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js.
- API-based backend written in Nodejs with Express and Loopback, using MongoDB.
- Deploy and maintain web applications on physical server and cloud server (AWS, GCP, Alibaba Cloud).

Main projects:

Bvote: A blockchain based online voting system. Bvote have provided services for biggest companies and the Big Two major beauty pageants in Vietnam.

• Website: https://bvote.com.vn

• Technologies: ReactJs, ExpressJs (Nodejs), Gin (Golang) HyperLedger Fabric, MongoDb, Docker, AWS.

Bytepay: A payment gateway that connect with multi banks and e-wallet to provide Collection / Payment on behalf services.

• Website: https://bytepay.vn

• Technologies: ReactJs, NestJs (Nodejs), Go-mirco (Golang), Gin (Golang), MySQL, Redis, gRPC, RabbitMQ, Docker, AWS.

Boffice: An Enterprise Management Platform that provides an online working environment on the Internet, designed and built on the basis of cloud computing technology.

• Website: https://boffice.bytesoft.vn

Technologies: ReactJs, NestJs (Nodejs), MySql, Docker, AWS

iRadar Data / Full Stack Developer

2018 - 2019: Ottawa, Canada

- Design UI mocks, site flows, wireframes and high fidelity prototypes using Adobe XD and Figma.
- Design and develop full-stack solutions focused on solving use case from web UI, to backend and database.
- Create front-end interface for customer using JavaScript / HTML / CSS.
- Implemented new UI and templating system to improve UX and system flexibility.
- Integrate and use leading open source tools such as MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js.
- API-based backend written in Nodejs with Express and Loopback, using MongoDB.
- Deploy web applications on AWS, GCP and Heroku by using Docker.

Main project:

DoRemind: A smart calendar app which brings everything together to see the full events of your day.

• Technologies: ReactJs, ExpressJs (NodeJs), Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, GCP, Heroku

Minh Quan Company / Assistant manager

2014 - 2015: Hanoi, Vietnam

- Supported sales and business staff daily.
- Created invoices and process customer payments.
- Called vendors to check on orders, schedule deliveries, and coordinate payments.
- Attended vendor meetings with executives to log notes and manage presentations.
- Worked closely with General Manager to drive a guest focused sales strategy.
- Used information technology to record sales figures, for data analysis and forward planning.
- Updated the company website.

Education

Algonquin College / Computer Programming Diploma

2016 – 2018: Ottawa, Canada Dean's Honours List

Ming Chuan University / Business Management Degree

2011 – 2015: Taipei, Taiwan

Southeast Asian Foreign Student Scholarship